santaclaraca.gov 2019-05-23

# Privacy Policy | City of Santa Clara

Your privacy is important to us. The following privacy policy outlines how your personal information will be handled by the City of Santa Clara while using this site.

Our Commitment to Your Privacy and Security

The City of Santa Clara (the City) has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate the City's firm commitment to privacy and the security of your personal information. The following information explains our policy regarding any personal information you may supply to us when visiting the [santaclaraca.gov](http://santaclaraca.gov/) domain.

The City's goal in collecting personal information online is to provide you with the most effective service possible. By understanding your needs and preferences, the City will be in the better position to provide you with improved service. Our goal is to protect your online information in the same manner that we protect citizen and business information obtained through other means. 

Your personal information will not be collected through the City’s website unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (e.g. sending an e-mail, filling out a Web form, etc.). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature of this Web site.

Personally Identifiable Information We Collect   
Personal information we collect from you and store in our databases/servers:

  * Your first and last name 
    
  * Your account personal identification number (PIN) 
    
  * Your client barcode (if applicable) 
    
  * Your email address 
    
  * Your phone number
    
  * Your business certificate account number
    
  * Your preparer name, phone number and digital signature

Information we capture but do not store in our databases/servers:

  * Your credit card billing address 
    
  * Your credit card type 
    
  * Your credit card number and card security code (CSC)
    
  * The name on your card 
    
  * Your credit card expiration date 

What We Do to Secure Your Information  
We store your personal information in databases on servers located behind a firewall in order to protect against the unauthorized access to, or the compromise of, information contained on our servers. 

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. When you login to view your account information, we ensure your privacy by encrypting your password, and related information sent between your browser and our server using industry standard 128-bit or greater cryptography so that if this information is intercepted, it cannot be read. 

However, you should know that in the present technological environment, no security measures are perfect, and that neither we nor any other Internet site can fully eliminate these security risks.

Should there be an unauthorized access or suspected compromise of your personal information on our servers, we will immediately notify you through a written letter or other means so that you will be able to quickly take steps to prevent possible identity theft. 

How Your Information Is Used   
The City endeavors to keep all personal information collected through its website secure, and to maintain the confidentiality of such information.  To that end, the City does not share or sell any such information collected through its website with any categories of third parties unless required to do so pursuant to state or federal law.  The City may be required by law to share such information in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings.

Email Address   
On certain occasions, we may request your email address for purposes of correspondence or for other City business. The City will not share email addresses with anyone outside the City or disclose user information to any third party, unless required to do so pursuant to state or federal law. 

Log Files   
The City does not release any information about the collection of IP addresses to any third party except when required to do so pursuant to state or federal law. The City's website archives web server log files in order to create aggregate statistical reports, detect errors at the website, and implement security protocols. However, these aggregate reports do not contain any personally identifiable information, nor does the City regularly make any attempt to link the server log files with any particular individual. The web log files are eventually deleted. 

Direct Mail   
In the future, the City may use the personal data provided online to send you information about the City services and upcoming civic activities. We will neither sell nor provide your personal information for any other direct mail activities, unless required to do so pursuant to state or federal law. 

Security   
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

Other Websites   
This site contains links to other sites. The City is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. 

Contacting the Website  
If you would like to review or request changes to your information, or if you have any questions about this privacy policy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website -- including a request to review and/or modify your personal information that has been collected through this site -- you can contact the Web Manager listed below, either via email or letter.   

**Web Manager**  - [webmanager@santaclaraca.gov](mailto:webmanager@santaclaraca.gov) 

**City of Santa Clara**

**1500 Warburton Avenue**

**Santa Clara, CA 95050**

If your request concerns review and/or modification of your personal information, please so state in your communication to the City, and provide either a valid email address or mailing address to which the City can respond.  The City will respond to your communication within ten (10) days, setting forth a date and time by which your personal information will be gathered and prepared for your review.  If you submit a request in writing that the City modify your personal information, the City will review your request and notify you of its decision. 

Cookies  
This Web site uses "cookies." A cookie contains unique information a Web site can use to track various categories of information, such as IP address, browser version, and browser preferences. Cookies created on your computer by using this Web site do not contain personally identifying information. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer. If you choose not to accept a cookie on your computer, it will not prevent or prohibit you from gaining access to or using this site. 

Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy  
We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the Site. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site. Information we gather is subject to the Policy in effect at the time of use. It is your responsibility to review this Policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with all of its terms.  
  
Effective Date: May 11, 2017
